<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Greetings - Articles</title>
    <description>Welcome to my creative world...</description>
    <link>
    http://localhost:4000</link>
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Stuck on your IB IAs? Fear not!</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Resources coming soon!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Including a reflection on my Math Applications Higher-Level IA on Fourier 
Analysis!!!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
        <pubDate>Wed, 28 Dec 2022 05:18:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>
        http://localhost:4000/i-have-a-dream</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/i-have-a-dream</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>The Ultimate List of IB Exam Revision Resources</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Dear IB warriors,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is a list of some resources by IB teachers, graduates, etc., that will hopefully help you through your IB journey. In my IB days I searched around a lot, saved way too many links, and narrowed down some of the best resources out there. These currently relate to the external assessments, but I’m also working on resources for IA’s.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Math Applications &amp;amp; Interpretations&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.christosnikolaidis.com/en/mai-exercise/&quot;&gt;Lots of exercises&lt;/a&gt; We love practice problems!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.revisionvillage.com/ib-math-applications-and-interpretation-hl/practice-exams/mock-exams-set-1-paper-1/&quot;&gt;Mock Exams by Revision Village&lt;/a&gt; There are several sets, supposed to be IB-style mocks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sites.google.com/view/ibnotes2020/mathematics?authuser=0&quot;&gt;Notes Kindly Shared by Other IB Students&lt;/a&gt;. I didn’t actually use these, since I prefer to make my own notes to avoid falling into passive learning. Nevertheless, these do look quite thorough. Here’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://yuvalamichay.wordpress.com/ib-mathematics-notes-2014-syllabus/&quot;&gt;another collection of notes&lt;/a&gt; by a student.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Biology&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://mysciencesquad.weebly.com/ib-exam-review.html&quot;&gt;Test Taking Tips&lt;/a&gt;
Scroll all the way through! Lots of resources on this page&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://studynova.com/guide/biology/cell-biology/&quot;&gt;Overview of HL and SL topics&lt;/a&gt;
Could use this as a checklist to see if you’ve covered all bases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sites.google.com/a/canacad.ac.jp/sl-hl-1-biology-4-ferguson/previous-essay-questions&quot;&gt;Exam-Style Questions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Psychology&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ibpublishing.ibo.org/d_3_psych_gui_1702_1/apps/dpapp/guide.html?doc=d_3_psych_gui_1702_1_e&amp;amp;part=4&amp;amp;chapter=1&quot;&gt;Glossary of command terms&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.themantic-education.com/ibpsych/2016/10/26/evaluating-psychological-studies-quantitative/&quot;&gt;Evaluating Psychological Studies (Quantitative)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Biological Approach&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://ibpsychologynotes.blogspot.com/2012/05/biological-level-of-analysis.html&quot;&gt;Notes/Essay Outlines: Biological Level of Analysis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ibpsychhelp.wordpress.com/epbloaevolution/&quot;&gt;A Detailed LAQ Essay Plan&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://ibpsychhelp.wordpress.com/epbloageneticsethics/&quot;&gt;another one by ibpsychhelp&lt;/a&gt; for the LAQ “Discuss ethical considerations in research into genetic influences on behaviour”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://psychtutor.weebly.com/genetics-and-behaviour.html&quot;&gt;Notes/Ideas&lt;/a&gt; for the LAQ “With reference to relevant to research studies, to what extent does genetic inheritance influence behaviour?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sociocultural Approach&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://ibpsychologynotes.blogspot.com/2012/05/notes-sociocultural-level-of-analysis.html&quot;&gt;Notes/Essay Outlines: Sociocultural Level of Analysis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Paper 3&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.themantic-education.com/ibpsych/2018/12/06/practice-paper-3-observation-of-hospitals-mark-scheme/&quot;&gt;Practice Paper 3 - Observation of Hospitals&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.psychologyib.com/ib-psychology-blog/category/paper-3-hl-exam&quot;&gt;IB PSYCHOLOGY PAPER 3 PRACTICE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://ibpsychrevision.blogspot.com/p/qualitative-research.html&quot;&gt;Some Paper 3 notes - Qualitative Research&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;IB Spanish Ab initio&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://spanish4teachers.org/ibspanishabinitioresources/&quot;&gt;Collection of Resources&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://app.memrise.com/course/135820/ib-spanish-ab-initio-wordlist/16/&quot;&gt;Compilation of Vocab&lt;/a&gt; and more &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.brainscape.com/packs/ib-spanish-ab-initio-8198720&quot;&gt;vocab decks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.antonioluna.org/p/text-types.html&quot;&gt;Know your text types!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://sraplath.weebly.com/ab-initio-2.html&quot;&gt;Helpful Documents&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;English Lang &amp;amp; Lit resources coming!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
        <pubDate>Mon, 26 Dec 2022 10:20:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>
        http://localhost:4000/down-the-rabbit-hole</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/down-the-rabbit-hole</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Projects</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Want more IB study tips and strategies? Check out the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/@studywithjo8713&quot;&gt;videos&lt;/a&gt; I made the summer after graduating from the IB programme. There are 
also a couple of music covers on that channel - feel free to listen, or ignore.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        
        <pubDate>Mon, 26 Dec 2022 05:18:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>
        http://localhost:4000/the-businessman-and-fisherman</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/the-businessman-and-fisherman</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>18 Lessons to Conclude 18</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Do something out of your comfort zone everyday.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Mon, 26 Dec 2022 05:18:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>
        http://localhost:4000/out-to-sea</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/out-to-sea</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>A Quote to Start Off My Day</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;“How many hours are there in a mile? Is yellow square or round? Probably half the questions we ask - half our great theological and metaphysical problems - are like that.”&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Mon, 26 Dec 2022 03:18:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>
        http://localhost:4000/the-purpose-of-education</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/the-purpose-of-education</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Merry Christmas</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Merry Christmas Eve!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/rq3VieuCpuk?start=27&quot; title=&quot;YouTube video player&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sat, 24 Dec 2022 11:45:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>
        http://localhost:4000/gettysburg-address</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/gettysburg-address</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>First Post</title>
        
          <description>&lt;h4 id=&quot;heading4&quot;&gt;A &quot;Brief&quot; Introduction&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I hope to achieve with this writing corner of my website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One, writing forces me to think. I write in the hopes of learning, and I hope to not forget, that if some forceful expression of opinion should ever escape in these pages, to afterward test the merits of my own thoughts against those wiser and more experienced. I hope to especially revive an appreciation of the wisdom of ages past, for as CS Lewis argued in one of his essays in “On Stories: And Other Essays on Literature”, those born into the same times, even while disagreeing with each other on every contemporary topic they argue over, are still usually operating within the same framework of looking at the world. Our times and milieu have already instructed us (though none of us chose this teacher) on what the important topics to argue over are, what the important questions to ask are (and which ones are apparently old and worn out), and what approaches should guide or delineate our search for answers or solutions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But lest I simply dwell in the past, I must obviously explore the knowledge of those living and breathing and walking as well. I mean, I’m a student of computer science. Which, well, sort of didn’t exist for basically all of human civilization. While I would love to start documenting my journey through CS at some point, I’ve only been in this world for a year, whereas I’ve been writing and running and testing and debugging life.cpp ever since it popped out of the womb. That’s no excuse of course, as with anything there is always more room to grow. Yet, going back to the why of starting this “blog” or whatever this is, in comparison, at the moment writing about or reading about programming wouldn’t really make me a better programmer as much as actually getting my hands dirty (e.g., figuring out jekyll). But I suppose we must all start somewhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Essentially, this corner is just a small casual thing, to foster self-reflection and intentional dialogue, and growth. And moreover, to start conversations, so if you would like to further discuss anything here of interest, you will not find a reluctant conversationalist. All objections, reflections, etc, are welcome. An online platform is certainly useful for disseminating experiences and ideas. But the written expression of one’s personal opinions for the sake of making one’s voice heard in the noise is &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; my primary purpose. In fact I am rather adversive to the idea of anyone weighing my words here with regards to any matter too heavily.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Plus, there are many whose stories deserve voice and attention much more than mine. So, if there are more important things you need to be attending to, than, say, reading about the musings of an 18-year-old, why are you here? You’re given &lt;a href=&quot;https://theartofliving.com/time-quotes/&quot;&gt;700,000 hours in this lifetime give or take, sleeping through 152,000, eating and drinking through 45,000, and pooping (etc.) through 10,000&lt;/a&gt;. I know, I’ve rolled my eyes at such self-helpy words, but they usually contain some grain of truth and sometimes we are most blind to the obvious, so it wouldn’t hurt to throw in a reminder here, if just for myself (Good thing re-reading one’s past writing is slightly more tolerable than watching or hearing videos or recordings of onself).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyhow, as I have already gone on several tangents in this “introduction”, 
we’re off to a fantastic start.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TL;DR
Some things to expect, though not an exhaustive list:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Links for IB students (a continuation of my YT channel, if you will)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Reflections on books, art, things I’m learning.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lots of photos including, but not limited to, way too many sunset photos I’ve taken
over the years.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        
        <pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2022 05:18:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>
        http://localhost:4000/looking-glass-house</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/looking-glass-house</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>A Full and Comprehensive Style Test</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;This is just an &lt;em&gt;ipsis verbis&lt;/em&gt; copy of the first example running on the &lt;a href=&quot;http://demo.ghost.io&quot;&gt;Ghost Demo&lt;/a&gt;. This shows how you can use html styling to achieve your hopes.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sat, 27 Sep 2014 06:18:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>
        http://localhost:4000/a-full-and-comprehensive-style-test</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/a-full-and-comprehensive-style-test</guid>
      </item>
      
    
  </channel>
</rss>
